What makes you different makes you dangerous.
Divergent is a action, adventure, science fiction film directed by Neil Burger.
In a world divided into factions based on personality types, Tris learns
that she's been classified as Divergent and won't fit in.
When she discovers a plot to destroy Divergents, Tris and the mysterious Four
must find out what makes Divergents dangerous before it's too late.
Beatrice 'Tris' Prior, played by Shailene Woodley.
Tobias 'Four' Eaton, played by Theo James.
Christina, played by Zoë Kravitz.
Peter Hayes, played by Miles Teller.
Eric Coulter, played by Jai Courtney.
Caleb Prior, played by Ansel Elgort.
Divergent is a 2014 American dystopian science fiction action film directed
by Neil Burger, based on the 2011 novel by Veronica Roth.
The film is the first installment in The Divergent Series and was produced by Douglas Wick, Lucy
Fisher, and Pouya Shahbazian, with a screenplay by Evan Daugherty and Vanessa Taylor.
It stars Shailene Woodley, Theo James, Ashley Judd, Jai Courtney, Ray Stevenson, Zoë
Kravitz, Miles Teller, Tony Goldwyn, Ansel Elgort, Maggie Q, and Kate Winslet.
The story takes place in a dystopian and post-apocalyptic Chicago where
people are divided into distinct factions based on human virtues.
Beatrice Prior is warned that she is Divergent and thus
will never fit into any one of the factions.
Soon, she learns that a sinister plot is brewing
in the seemingly perfect society.
Development of Divergent began in March 2011 when Summit Entertainment picked up the film rights to the
novel with Douglas Wick and Lucy Fisher's production company Red Wagon Entertainment.
Principal photography began April 16, 2013, and concluded on July 16,
2013, with re-shoots taking place from January 24–26, 2014.
Production mostly took place in Chicago.
Divergent was released on March 21, 2014, in the United States.
The film received mixed reviews: although its action sequences and performances, notably Woodley's, were praised, critics deemed its execution
and handling of its themes to be generic and unoriginal, and compared it unfavorably to other young adult fiction adaptations.
The film grossed $288.9 million worldwide against its budget of $85 million.
It was released on DVD and Blu-ray on August 5, 2014.
A sequel, Insurgent, was released on March 20, 2015, in
the United States and other countries.
A third film, Allegiant, was released on March 18, 2016.
A fourth and final film, Ascendant, was never produced.
The film explores themes of mind control, future, based
on novel or book, dystopia, injection.
The tone is thought_provoking.